siteadvisor.pl 2010-06-22

# Virus, Spam, Spyware Protection Software for Your PC | McAfee

Print

Effective on: May 10, 2008 

This Policy discloses the privacy practices for the site mcafee.com and this Policy applies to all of the products, services, and websites offered by McAfee, Inc. or its subsidiaries or affiliated companies (collectively McAfee’s “Services”). 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact the Privacy Program Office of McAfee, Inc. by emailing [privacy@mcafee.com](mailto:privacy@mcafee.com), by calling 972-963-7902, or by sending a letter to Privacy Program Office McAfee, Inc. 3965 Freedom Circle, Santa Clara, CA 95054. In the event that you do not receive a response, please contact the Consumer Privacy Response Team of McAfee, Inc. by emailing [consumer_privacy_response_team@mcafee.com](mailto:consumer_privacy_response_team@mcafee.com) or by sending a letter to Consumer Privacy Response Team at 5000 Headquarters Drive, Plano, Texas 75024.

McAfee complies with the EU Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

McAfee recognizes that privacy is important. As a security company, we understand the need for you to maintain control over your personal data when using the Internet. This statement provides the following information for you:

  1. What information we collect
  2. How we use the information
  3. With whom we share the information
  4. How you can **opt-in to or opt-out of** data collection and use
  5. Our policy on correcting and updating personally identifiable information
  6. Our policy on deleting or deactivating your name from our database

## What Information We Collect

We collect and store some or all of the following information about our users: name; email address; IP Address; and billing information, such as address, phone number, and credit card number. If you do not wish to have your credit card number stored, please contact [Customer Support](http://home.mcafee.com/root/support.aspx). We also receive and may store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many Web sites, we use "cookies" and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses www.mcafee.com. More information on our use of "cookies" can be found below. We may combine the information you submit under your account with other information from other McAfee Services or third parties in order to improve the quality of our services and provide you with a better experience. 

In order to tailor our subsequent communications to you and continuously improve our products and services (including registration), we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, experience with our products, and more detailed contact preferences.

## Web Applications 

We may also employ certain applications, such as the various components of McAfee Services, to retrieve information about your computer system to assist us in the provision and support of Services that you have chosen to subscribe to or use. This information is essential to enable us to provide you with quality service; and for this reason, there is no opt-out available for this information collection. 

## Use of Data 

McAfee uses your information to better understand your needs, provide you with the Services you have requested and provide you with better service. We may use your information to help you complete a transaction (including fulfillment of orders and promotional offers), to communicate back to you, to inform you of and update you on Services and benefits, to personalize our Web sites for you, to provide you Services and to manage and renew your subscription(s). Credit card numbers are used only for payment processing, maintenance of your subscription and fraud protection, and are not used for other purposes without your permission. 

## Use of Your Email Address 

If you provide us with your email address when you register as a customer or make a purchase from us, we or our trusted business partners may send you email with recommendations or notices of new products, prices, and services. This email may include paid advertisements from one or more of our trusted business partners. At the time you receive a confirmation of purchase or registration, you will be given the opportunity to **opt into or out of** such communications. If you do not initially choose to opt out, you may still block future email of this type, simply by following the unsubscribe instructions that accompany all such communications. 

Separately, we send service notifications via email to keep you informed about the status of your service orders or accounts; and to provide updates, upgrades, security alerts, security information and technical notices. These messages are essential to the maintenance of your subscription and the functionality of our Services. Therefore there is no opt-out available for service notifications and these messages cannot be blocked.

We follow best practices for email marketing and customer contact, as well as urge our trusted business partners and vendors to do the same. For more information on our practices, please see "Use of Data." More information on third parties with whom we may share your information is provided below under "Special Relationships."

We may share with third parties certain pieces of visitor and customer information that is statistically aggregated, and consists of non-personal information. In this circumstance, we do not disclose to these entities any information that could be used to personally identify you, such as your name, email address, account, password, or transaction history.

## Special Relationships 

McAfee has a number of relationships with vendors with whom we may share your personal information for the purpose of providing a service, fulfilling an order or completing a transaction. For example, we use certain vendors for the purpose of providing credit card transaction and check processing services. These vendors verify your purchase information, such as credit card number or checking account number, and authorize your transaction. In doing so, these vendors have access to data about users, but they are prohibited from using this information for any other purpose. 

## Digital River 

Digital River powers some of McAfee's e-commerce, and in doing so collects information about users, including credit card information. When a user purchases a product from the McAfee Store powered by Digital River, information about the customer and the purchase are shared with McAfee. Credit card numbers are used only for payment processing and fraud protection, and are not used for other purposes without your permission. 

Digital River, on behalf of McAfee, may occasionally notify you of special offers, new products, services, promotions, and other similar information. This will only be done with your consent. If you gave consent to receive email from Digital River, on behalf of McAfee, any emails you receive will have clear unsubscribe instructions. For more information, read  [Digital River's privacy policy](http://corporate.digitalriver.com/store/driv/Corp/sectionName.company/subSectionName.corpPolicies/page.corpPolicies#privacy)

The information shared between McAfee and vendors is processed only for the purpose of performing contractual obligations, and no processing activity will be carried out by McAfee without prior notice to users, and where necessary, with users' consent. McAfee hereby expressly disclaims any liability for the data processing activities of the vendors above specified, which will act as independent data processing Controllers. Please read carefully such vendors' Privacy Policies before providing your personal data.

## Links 

Our site contains links to other Web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are 'clicking' to another Web site. As McAfee does not accept liability for misuse of any information by any Web site controller to which we may link, we encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites, as their privacy policies may differ from ours. 

If you choose to take advantage of an offer from one of our trusted business partners, you may be providing information to such partner directly. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of such partners, as their policies may differ from ours.

## Cookies 

McAfee uses software tags called "cookies" to identify customers when they visit our site. Cookies are used to remember user preferences and maximize performance of our services. Additionally, cookies help us to identify returning users so that we don't ask them to enter their email and password with every visit. The information we collect with cookies is not sold, rented, or shared with any outside parties. We also ask that you fill in your first name and last name in a box so that our customer support services can identify and assist you in case of login problems. We cannot provide subscription services to users who do not give their consent to the data processing carried out through cookies or whose browsers are set to reject all cookies. 

McAfee uses an ad server for the serving and/or targeting of ads, promotions and other marketing messages. Cookies may be used to control the type and/or frequency of ads, promotions or other marketing messages the customer views.

We may also use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on our site. These companies may employ cookies and action tags (also known as single pixel gifs or web beacons) to measure advertising effectiveness. Any information that these third parties collect via cookies and action tags is non-personal and anonymous.

McAfee also uses third parties for serving and/or targeting of ads, promotions, and other marketing messages. To do this, such third parties collect non-personal information through the use of cookies about the types of sites you visit and other non-personally identifiable information about you in order to deliver advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you. In the course of serving advertisements or providing other marketing services, third parties may place or recognize a unique, non-personally identifiable cookie in your browser. In providing these services, third parties do not link personal information (such as your name, land address or telephone number) to your Web site visits.

## Log Files

McAfee maintains log files of the traffic that visits our site. When you use McAfee Services, our servers may automatically record information that your browser or you send when you visit a website. These log files may include information such as your requests, IP address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your system. 

## Feedback 

We collect user feedback, and we cull testimonials that appear on the site from our feedback form, but only after we have duly informed and obtained permission from the senders. We also post surveys on our site to better understand our user population. These surveys are voluntary and anonymous, and the results are statistically aggregated so that no personal information can be associated with survey results. To the extent you provide any comments or suggestions to McAfee, McAfee shall have the right to retain and use any such comments or suggestions regarding the Services in current or future Services, without further compensation to you or further approval by you. 

## Access/Correct/Update/Delete User Information

Users can access, update, correct, or delete most of their personal information held by McAfee by clicking on the "[My Account](http://home.mcafee.com/root/myaccount.aspx)" link, by contacting Customer Support [here](http://home.mcafee.com/root/support.aspx), and by contacting McAfee, Inc.'s Privacy Program Office at [privacy@mcafee.com](mailto:privacy@mcafee.com). Users may have all of their personal information deleted or cancel their accounts entirely by contacting Customer Support. We will respond to your request as quickly as possible, and in no event longer than 30 days from receipt of your request. 

## Information Security

All information gathered on the site is stored and maintained in secure facilities that limit access to authorized personnel only. The McAfee web sites are regularly tested for security breaches to ensure that all information collected is secure from unauthorized viewing. Personal customer information is protected in transit via HTTPS and SSL security. Credit card information is transmitted with multiple layers of security, including encryption in storage and SSL in transit. 

## Retention of Information

McAfee will keep personal information of its users for as long as they are registered subscribers or users of our products, and for a reasonable time thereafter. 

## Legal Disclaimer

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site. 

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this policy at any time by simply posting such addition or modification on the Web Site. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an e-mail or via a prominent notice on our site. 

## Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us by emailing [privacy@mcafee.com](mailto:privacy@mcafee.com), by calling 972-963-7902, by contacting [Customer Support](http://home.mcafee.com/root/support.aspx), or by sending a letter to Privacy Program Office, McAfee, Inc. 3965 Freedom Circle, Santa Clara, CA 95054.
